# **JOHN SCALES**

# **Aspiring Software Engineer**

Whittier, CA 90601

j scales@aol.com

626-379-8711

I'm John, a 23-year-old aspiring software engineer. I have experience with web dev, game dev, and mobile dev and 9 months of professional experience with PLC and HMI programming along with some Python and other scripting langs with a sprinkle of web dev.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer



# WORK EXPERIENCE -----

# **Industrial Control Systems Designer**

**Industrial Logic Systems, LLC.** - Anaheim, CA January 2020 to Present

- I mainly program HMIs using ladder logic.
- A typical program requires going over the customer requirements, creating logical architecture (in some cases), programming the PLC, and HMI (if HMI required).
- It's mainly a waterfall process, but I am familiar with agile & scrum.
- Programming HMIs requires some artistic taste and UI design skills. As well as some logic and communication driver knowledge.
- I have worked on projects for Control Dynamics Corp (Acid Leach Process), Army Corps of Engineers (Dredge Quality Management), North Island Naval Air Station (F35 Testing), Rammstein Air (Spray Booth), Siegfried Pharma (Water Purification & pH System), and others.
- I have also taken the initiative on some projects and made Python scripts in an effort to lessen the cost for my employer to deploy systems for DQM. Scripts run on a Raspberry Pi instead of full PCs since the tasks are light.

#### Server

Oakmont Senior Living - Brea, CA December 2016 to April 2017

- Memorized the names of over 80 residents.
- Clean dining room and kitchen.
- Setup dining room and prepared food.
- · Waited tables & handled transactions



**EDUCATION** 

#### **Bachelor's in Computer Science**

California State University-Fullerton - Whittier, CA September 2018 to Present Expected Graduation: December 2020

# Associate in General Studies Emphasis in Science and Mathematics

Rio Hondo College - Whittier, CA September 2015 to June 2018



#### **SKILLS**

#### Languages:

#### **Primary:**

C++, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

#### Others:

x86, MIPS, Shell Script, R, PHP, MySQL, Ladder Logic, Lua

# OS':

Windows, MacOS, iOS, Android, Linux, Linux Mint, Ubuntu, Raspian

#### **Technologies & Tools:**

Git, Bash, Tar, Docker, Clang, GNU GCC, Atom, Vagrant, Bootstrap, GitHub, Node.js

#### **Programs:**

Visual Studio Code, Atom, Unity, Unreal Engine, Visual Studio, Postman, Microsoft Office, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Adobe Photoshop, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Illustrator, Magix Vegas Pro, Autodesk Maya, GIMP, Davinci Resolve, GraphicsMagick, OBS, Audacity



LINKS

http://johnscales.site

https://github.com/JESIII

https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-scales



#### **ASSESSMENTS**

# Numerical Reasoning Skills — Proficient

-----

August 2019

Quickly and accurately performing basic mathematical operations, recognizing numerical sequences, and interpreting graphs. Full results: <a href="Proficient">Proficient</a>

# Food Safety — Proficient

February 2019

Knowledge of proper food handling, storage, and equipment use for preventing the spread of foodborne illness.

Full results: Proficient

#### **Verbal Communication** — **Expert**

February 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to effectively convey information when speaking.

Full results: Expert

# **Analyzing Data** — Expert

October 2020

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: Expert

# Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Expert

October 2020

Knowledge of various Microsoft Excel features, functions, and formulas.

Full results: Expert

# **Programming Fundamentals — Proficient**

October 2020

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical competency.

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.



# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION -----

#### Projects:

# **Bad Decision Maker iOS App:**

\_\_\_\_\_

An app I made for my mobile development class, from scratch using Xcode and SwiftUI. https://apps.apple.com/us/app/baddecisionmaker/id1505251734

# **ZirShares Fund Allocator:**

A web app I made for my own use. It can market balance a selection of stocks just like real ETFs like SPY and VOO. It can also balance your stocks with your desired weights.

It maximizes shares according to your budget.

Made with JavaScript, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS.

https://johnscales.site/etf.html

#### Game Buddy:

A website made by me and 5 others in my Software Engineering class over the course of a semester.

The entire UI was made by me and my teammate Oscar.

I did the entire homepage on my own, code, and design. The games list was a collaboration between me and Oscar, him doing the javascript for the dynamic loading and me doing some of the design for the cards and some sorting functionality. The games pages were an equal effort by me and Oscar. I did a lot of the javascript and he added some QOL features and did a good portion of the javascript.

The dev pages were done by me.

The rest was the rating and login system, hosting, and database that was done by the rest of the team.

Made with HTML, JavaScript, SASS, PHP, XXAMP, AWS, Bootstrap, Node.js.

https://johnscales.site/gamebuddy.html

#### Acid Leach System for Control Dynamics Corp.:

This was a PLC and HMI program that controls the Acid Leach Tank system for Synthetic Textiles, Inc. https://www.synthetictextilesinc.com/

The program controls 2 tanks, 2 pumps, and 6 valves and goes through Acid Leach cycles to automatically create the textiles for the company. I also programmed an HMI for the project to configure and control the system graphically and see the process. This program is fully implemented and in use at the site.

Made with Ladder Logic, Productivity Suite, CMore.